So, building your webcam profile is like building any business.
You build it from the ground up.
We all start from the beginning with no clients, with no content, and we have
to build up our
business in order to make it lucrative and worthwhile.
So the great thing about webcam is that it can fit into your life, whatever
that looks
like, whether it's a couple of hours a week, a few hours a day, or it's going
to be your
full-time job that you're spending all your time on, it's great because it can
fit around
you.
However, that does mean that we can become complacent, that we can kind of
leave it in
the background, dip in here and there, which is fine, but if you really want to
make the
most of webcam, if you really want to make good money and grow your profile and
be able
to rely on the financial side of this, then it's all about consistency and
planning and
having goals.
In the beginning, it's good to scope it out, see what hours work best for you,
when do
you get your best clients, when do you feel best going online, what works for
you around
your other responsibilities.
Once you've got an idea about what works for you, you can begin to plan.
So I think it's always a good idea to have a bit of a monthly plan, a weekly
plan, what
hours are you going to go online?
You can let your clients know when you're going to be there.
Keeping up regulars is the key to building up financial security through webcam
and that
will come with consistency when you're coming online at the same times, when
you're speaking
to the same people and you're building your profile around what these people
like to chat
with you about and what makes you you.
Keeping motivation and consistency is so important.
As with any business, we can have quiet times, quiet days and we can get a bit
disheartened
and maybe think, ah, I'll go and come tomorrow, it wasn't so busy yesterday.
The thing is to stay consistent.
We don't stop selling something just because we have a quiet day.
We continue, we stay motivated, we stay on track and if we look at what we've
earned then
over the week or over the month rather than each day, we can look back and
think, ah, I've
earned a few hundred pounds or even a few thousand and it all worked out in the
end.
Those quiet times, they always come full circle if we're staying consistent.